Connecticut State Labor Council, AFL-CIO Records 1989.0080
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series VIII: Pamphlets, undated, 1940-1975
  - Socialized medicine (see: Health and welfare, Older population, Health care, Forand Bill, Anderson-King Bill)
  - Southern affairs, 1950-1958 (Box 108:, Folder 3198)
  - Speeches (see: Addresses)
  - Speeches and articles, J. M. Rourke, 1957 (Box 108:, Folder 3199)
  - State government, 1962-1965 (Box 108:, Folder 3200)
  - Statistics, 1952 (Box 108:, Folder 3201)
  - Stewards training (see: Workers education, Stewards training and grievance procedure)
  - Steel industry, 1952-1959 (Box 108:, Folder 3202)
  - Strikes, 1961-1962 (Box 108:, Folder 3203)
  - Structural unemployment (see: Unemployment)
  - Subversive activities, 1964, 1971 (Box 108:, Folder 3204)
  - Taft-Hartley, 1947-1963 (Box 108:, Folder 3205)
  - Talks, undated (Box 108:, Folder 3206)
  - Tariffs (see: Economics)
  - Taxation, 1960-1964 (Box 108:, Folder 3207)
  - Taxes (see: Taxation)
  - Television, undated (Box 108:, Folder 3208)
  - Tennessee Valley Authority, 1952-1959 (Box 108:, Folder 3209)
  - Time motion study (see: Industrial engineering)
  - Time tables, 1966 (Box 108:, Folder 3210)
  - Trade, 1963-1970 (Box 108:, Folder 3211)
  - Trade Adjustment Assistance Program, 1962 (Box 108:, Folder 3212)
  - Trade Expansion Act, 1962 (Box 108:, Folder 3213)
  - Trade Unions
    - General, 1950-1960 (Box 108:, Folder 3214)
    - Democratic action, 1957-1968 (Box 108:, Folder 3215)
    - Ethics (see: Trade union regulations and laws)
    - History, 1960 (Box 108:, Folder 3216)
    - International (see: Labor organizations, foreign and international)
    - Other countries, 1968-1969 (Box 109:, Folder 3217)
    - Regulations and laws, 1956-1969 (Box 109:, Folder 3218)
    - Songs, undated (Box 109:, Folder 3219)
  - Trade, education, 1958-1966 (Box 109:, Folder 3220)
  - Transportation, 1966-1967 (Box 109:, Folder 3221)
  - Trusts (see: Monopolies)
  - Truth in lending, 1965 (Box 109:, Folder 3222)
  - Truth in packaging, 1966 (Box 109:, Folder 3223)
  - Unamerican Activities Committee, 1964 (Box 109:, Folder 3224)
  - Under the Golden Dome (see: CT legislature 1963)
  - Unemployment
    - General, 1960-1964 (Box 109:, Folder 3225)
    - Compensation, 1965-1966 (Box 109:, Folder 3226)
    - Insurance, 1961-1965 (Box 109:, Folder 3227)
  - Union
    - Affairs, 1959-1966 (Box 109:, Folder 3228)
    - Contracts, 1955-1962 (Box 109:, Folder 3229)
    - Label, 1958-1970 (Box 109:, Folder 3230)
  - Unions, individual, 1947-1965 (Box 109:, Folder 3231-3232)
  - United Auto Workers, 1964-1969 (Box 109:, Folder 3233)
  - United Ownership Act, undated (Box 110:, Folder 3234)
  - United Nations, 1954 (Box 110:, Folder 3235)
  - United States
    - Politics and government, 1960-1964 (Box 110:, Folder 3236)
    - Social and economic conditions, 1963-1964 (Box 110:, Folder 3237)
    - Treaties, 1961 (Box 110:, Folder 3238)
  - Universal military service, 1958 (Box 110:, Folder 3239)
  - Urban affairs, 1964-1970 (Box 110:, Folder 3240)
  - Urban coalition, 1967 (Box 110:, Folder 3241)
  - Urban renewal (see: Urban affairs)
  - Utilities, 1963 (Box 110:, Folder 3242)
  - Veterans, 1960 (Box 110:, Folder 3243)
  - Vista, 1968 (Box 110:, Folder 3244)
  - Vocational training, 1960-1970 (Box 110:, Folder 3245)
  - Voting (see: Elections)
  - Wage collection laws (see: Labor legislation)
  - Wages (see: Wages and hours)
  - Wages and hours, 1962-1973 (Box 110:, Folder 3246)
  - Walsh-Healy Act (see: Wages and hours)
  - Welfare and pension plans, 1967-1973 (Box 110:, Folder 3247)
  - White collar workers (See: Labor force, white collar workers)
  - Witch hunts (see: Subversive activities, investigations)
  - Work stoppage (see: Unemployment)
  - Women, U.S., 1963-1969 (Box 110:, Folder 3248)
  - Worker education
    - General, 1957-1964 (Box 111:, Folder 3249-3250)
    - History, 1960-1961 (Box 111:, Folder 3251)
    - Industrial relations Center (see: Workers education, Courses, Programs)
    - International, 1956-1961 (Box 111:, Folder 3252)
    - Research studies, 1957-1961 (Box 111:, Folder 3253)
    - Stewards education and grievance procedure, 1960-1965 (Box 111:, Folder 3254)
    - Study and Teaching, undated (Box 111:, Folder 3255)
  - Workmen's compensation, 1957-1968 (Box 111:, Folder 3256)
  - Workmen's education (see: Workers education)
  - Youth employment, 1959-1964 (Box 111:, Folder 3257)
- Series IX: Betty Tianti, undated, 1970-1986
  - Subseries A: National and State Labor Organizations, undated, 1981-1985
    - Central Labor Councils, undated (Box 155)
    - Northeast AFL-CIO Council, undated
    - Other state federations, undated
    - Unaffiliated unions, undated
  - Subseries B: Local Affiliates, undated 1981-1985
    - Affiliated unions. Miscellaneous, undated
    - Boilermakers, undated
    - Building and construction trades, CT, undated
    - Carpenters, undated
    - Clothing and textile, amalgamated, undated
    - Communications workers, undated
    - Electrical workers, Brotherhood of, undated
    - Electronic workers ( IUE), undated
    - Engineers, operating ( IUOE), undated
    - Firefighters, undated
    - Food and commercial workers, United, undated
    - Furniture workers, undated
    - Glass, pottery and allied workers, undated
    - Government employees, American Federation of ( AFGE), undated
    - Health Care employees, New England, undated
    - Hotel employees and restaurant employees ( HERE), undated
    - Ironworkers, undated
    - Machinists ( IAMAW), undated
    - Office and professional employees ( OPEIO), undated
    - Oil, Chemical and atomic workers ( OCAW), undated
    - Painters, undated
    - Paperworkers, undated
    - Postal workers, undated
    - Police ( AFSCME Council), undated
    - Plumbers, undated
    - Printing and graphics, undated
    - Protective Services, undated
    - Rubber workers, undated
    - School administration, undated
    - Service Employees International Union ( SEIU), undated
    - Sheet metal workers, undated
    - State, county and municipal employees, American Federation of ( AFSCME), undated
    - Steelworkers, undated
    - Teachers, undated (Box 156)
    - Transportation workers, undated
    - Utility workers, undated
  - Subseries C: National AFL-CIO, undated, 1979-1985
    - Commercial Services, Department of, undated (Box 156)
    - Convention, National AFL-CIO, undated (Box 156)
    - Data Processing, Department of, undated (Box 156)
    - Donahue, Thomas R. (National, Secretary-Treasurer), undated (Box 156)
    - Driscoll, John (President Emeritus), undated (Box 156)
    - Education, Department of, undated (Box 156)
    - Health and Safety, undated (Box 156)
    - Holocaust Memorial campaign, undated (Box 156)
    - Housing Investment Trust, undated (Box 156)
    - Human Resource Development Trust, undated (Box 156)
    - Information, Department of, undated (Box 156)
    - Internal Affairs, Department of, undated (Box 156)
    - Kirkland, Lane (National President), undated (Box 156)
    - Labor Institute of Public Affairs (LIPA), undated (Box 156)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 156)
    - OSHA and Social Security, undated (Box 156)
    - Organization and Field Services, Department of, undated (Box 156)
    - Professional Employees (Women's Project) Department of, undated (Box 156)
    - Public Employees, undated (Box 156)
    - Public Relations, Department of, undated (Box 156)
    - Regional meetings, undated (Box 156)
    - Research, Department of, undated (Box 156)
    - Tianti, Betty (President), undated (Box 156)
    - Women Working for '84, undated (Box 156)
  - Subseries D: Staff/Committee Files, undated, 1981-1986
    - Affiliations and deaffiliations, undated (Box 157)
    - COPE Committee, 1986 (Box 186)
    - COPE (State), activities of director and staff, undated (Box 157)
    - Common Core Learning Consortium, 1986-1987 (Box 185)
    - Cuomo/COPE speech, 1983 (Box 157)
    - Delegate Plan for Democratic National Convention, 1984 (Box 157)
    - Election campaign letters, undated (Box 157)
    - Election preparation Solidarity Day III, undated (Box 157)
    - Executive Board, undated (Box 157)
    - Federal and state elections, undated (Box 157)
    - Financial data, undated; (3 fl) (Box 157)
    - Grassroots lobbying, undated (Box 157)
    - Governor's Taskforce on Family Violence, 1985 (Box 185)
    - Governor's Taskforce on the Homeless, 1984-1986 (Box 185)
    - Housing Advisory Committee, 1985-1986 (Box 185)
    - Labor Union Liaison Meeting, 1984 (Box 157)
    - Interview with members of Congress, undated (Box 157)
    - Mail, direct: COPE, undated (Box 157)
    - Norman Zolot memoranda, undated (Box 157)
    - Press releases, undated (Box 157)
    - Questionnaires (federal and state) COPE, undated (Box 157)
    - Staff meeting minutes, undated (Box 157)
    - State AFL-CIO News, undated (Box 157)
    - Standing committees, undated (Box 157)
      - CLC presidents, undated (Box 157)
      - Education, undated (Box 157)
      - Legislation, undated (Box 157)
    - Study Committee for Department of Revenue Services, 1987 (Box 185)
    - Taskforce on Independent Colleges and Universities, 1986 (Box 185)
  - Subseries E: Election Files, undated, 1970-1986
    - 1986 elections, undated (Box 187)
    - COPE, undated (Box 159)
      - Contributions, undated (Box 159)
      - Congressional leaflet material, undated (Box 159)
    - COPE budget, undated (Box 187)
    - COPE committee meetings, undated (Box 160)
      - Endorsements to convention, undated (Box 160)
    - Democratic National Party Conference, undated (Box 160)
    - Democratic Party, undated (Box 159)
    - Democratic Party, undated (Box 160)
    - Democratic Platform committee, undated (Box 160)
    - Election information, undated; (5 fl) (Box 158)
    - Election data and laws, undated (Box 158)
    - Elections, undated (Box 160)
    - Endorsed Senate/House candidate by Labor Council, undated (Box 159)
    - Executive Committee meeting, undated (Box 160)
    - Gubernatorial race, undated (Box 187)
    - Ted Kennedy, undated (Box 159)
    - Labor Friends of Chris Dodd, undated (Box 159)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 159)
    - Walter Mondale, undated (Box 160)
    - News clippings, undated (Box 159)
    - Presidential election, undated (Box 159)
    - Presidential race, undated (Box 159)
    - Responses to congressional questionnaires, undated (Box 159)
    - Salt Treaty Conference and information, undated (Box 159)
    - Senate letters (copies), undated (Box 160)
    - State Candidate questionnaire, undated (Box 187)
    - State representatives, undated (Box 158)
    - Statewide COPE meeting, undated (Box 160)
  - Subseries F: Legislative Files, undated, 1980-1985
    - State Legislative Conference, undated (Box 161)
    - Legislative bulletins, undated (Box 161)
    - Legislative issues, undated (Box 161)
    - Legislative issues: tax reform, undated (Box 161)
    - Legislative issues, undated; (2 fl) (Box 161)
    - Legislative sessions in CT, undated (Box 161)
  - Subseries G: Administrative Files, undated, 1981-1985
    - Notices to all affiliates, undated; (3 fl) (Box 162)
    - Activities, undated (Box 176)
    - Affiliates activities, undated (Box 176)
    - Affiliations, disaffiliations, undated (Box 176)
    - AFL-CIO News, undated (Box 176)
    - American Association of University Professors, undated (Box 162)
    - American Association of University Women, undated (Box 162)
    - American Institute for Free Labor Development, undated (Box 162)
    - American Institute for Free Labor Development, undated (Box 184)
    - Analysis Group, Inc., undated (Box 184)
    - Anti-Apartheid Committee, undated (Box 162)
    - Bates, Matthew, undated (Box 176)
    - Beck, Audrey, undated (Box 162)
    - C, undated (Box 184)
    - CCLU, undated (Box 184)
    - Center for Environmental Health, undated (Box 184)
    - Central America, Fact Finding Mission to, undated (Box 162)
    - Central Labor Council activities, undated (Box 176)
    - Charter Oak College, undated (Box 184)
    - Citizens to Protect CT's constitution, undated (Box 176)
    - Civil Rights, U.S. Commission on, undated (Box 162)
    - CLC Presidents' Committee, undated (Box 176)
    - Coalition of Labor Union Women, undated (Box 184)
    - Committee on Changing Situations at work, undated (Box 176)
    - Committee on Pay Equity, undated (Box 162)
    - Community Labor Alliance, undated (Box 162)
    - Community Services Committee, undated (Box 176)
    - Conflict Resolution, Association for, undated (Box 162)
    - Congress of CT Community Colleges, undated (Box 184)
    - Connecticash, undated (Box 162)
    - Connecticut, undated (Box 162)
      - Association for Human Services, undated (Box 184)
      - Business and Industry Association, undated (Box 162)
      - Civil Liberties Union, undated (Box 162)
      - Conference for Independent Colleges, undated (Box 184)
      - Construction Industries Association, undated (Box 162)
      - Constitution Convention, undated (Box 162)
      - Credit Union, undated (Box 162)
      - State University, Central, undated (Box 162)
      - University, undated (Box 162)
        - Health Center, undated (Box 162)
        - Labor Archives, undated (Box 162)
        - Labor Education Center, undated (Box 162)
    - Coors boycott, undated (Box 176)
    - COPE activities, undated (Box 176)
    - Convention, 31st Annual, 1986
      - Verbatim Proceedings, undated (Box 186)
      - Officers and committee reports, undated (Box 186)
      - Resolutions submitted, undated (Box 186)
    - D, undated (Box 184)
    - Democratic Platform `82-'84, undated (Box 163)
    - Democrats in CT, undated (Box 163)
    - Democratic National Community, undated (Box 163)
    - Dempsey Hospital, undated (Box 184)
    - Dodd, Chris, undated (Box 163)
    - Economic Education, CT Joint Council, undated (Box 163)
    - Education Committee, undated (Box 176)
    - Energy, undated (Box 184)
    - Energy crisis, undated (Box 163)
    - Executive Board, undated (Box 176)
    - Farm workers, undated (Box 163)
    - Financial data, undated (Box 176)
    - Freedom of Information, undated (Box 184)
    - Foreign visitors, undated (Box 176)
    - Hartford Manufacturers Group, undated (Box 163)
    - Health and Safety Committee, undated (Box 176)
    - Histadrut, undated (Box 163)
    - Housatanic Community College, undated (Box 163)
    - Humanities Council, undated (Box 163)
    - Hydro Quebec, undated (Box 176)
    - Income tax in CT, undated (Box 163)
    - Industrial alternatives, undated (Box 163)
    - Industrial relations, undated (Box 163)
    - Insurance Tort Reform, undated (Box 184)
    - International Year of the Child, undated (Box 163)
    - Interstate banking, undated (Box 184)
    - Ireland, undated (Box 163)
    - Ireland, undated (Box 184)
    - Israel, undated (Box 163)
    - Jobs for the Future, undated (Box 184)
    - Judicial nominations, undated (Box 163)
    - Judicial nominations, undated (Box 176)
    - K, undated (Box 184)
    - Kershner scholarship, undated (Box 163)
    - Kershner scholarship, undated (Box 184)
    - Labor Education Center Advisory Committee, undated (Box 184)
    - LEAP, undated (Box 163)
    - LEAP, undated (Box 184)
    - Letters to the editor, undated (Box 163)
    - Letters to Editors, undated (Box 184)
    - Literacy, undated (Box 184)
    - Machinists contract negotiations, undated (Box 176)
    - Meany, George, undated (Box 163)
    - Monitor Productions, undated (Box 163)
    - N, undated (Box 184)
    - National Association of Government Employees, undated (Box 163)
    - Naugatuck Valley Project, undated (Box 184)
    - New Britain's work towards Policy/Solidarity, undated (Box 163)
    - New building, undated (Box 184)
    - New England Board of Higher Education, undated (Box 163)
    - New England Board of Higher Education, undated (Box 184)
    - New England Rural Leadership Program, undated (Box 163)
    - New Haven, undated (Box 184)
    - News releases, undated (Box 176)
    - Northeast Utilities, undated (Box 184)
    - Northeast/Midwest Congress Coalition, undated (Box 164)
    - Occupational Disease Compensation, undated (Box 164)
    - Olson, John Secretary-Treasurer, undated (Box 176)
    - OPEIU contract negotiations, undated (Box 176)
    - OPM Comprehensive Planning, undated (Box 176)
    - Organization for Research and Training, undated (Box 184)
    - OSHA, undated (Box 164)
    - OSHA, undated (Box 184)
    - Pastoral letter—Catholic social teaching/US economy, undated (Box 164)
    - PATCO, undated (Box 164)
    - Personal mail (BLT), undated (Box 164)
    - Philip Randolph Institute, undated (Box 184)
    - Physicians and Dentists organization, undated (Box 164)
    - Plant closing information, undated (Box 164)
    - Plant Closing information, undated (Box 184)
    - Privitization, undated (Box 184)
    - Project vote, undated (Box 164)
    - Property Tax relief study commission, undated (Box 164)
    - Quits and fires, undated (Box 164)
    - Red Cross disaster planning, undated (Box 184)
    - Republicans, undated (Box 184)
    - Resumes/biographies, undated (Box 164)
    - Rourke, Joseph, undated (Box 176)
    - School kits, undated (Box 176)
    - South Africa, undated (Box 184)
    - South Africa, Bishop Tutu, undated (Box 164)
    - Speeches, Testimonies, undated (Box 176)
    - Staff meetings, undated (Box 176)
    - Stover, Keith, undated (Box 176)
    - Strike Assistance Committee, undated (Box 176)
    - Taft seminars, undated (Box 164)
    - Tax reform Symposium, undated (Box 164)
    - Testimonials, undated (Box 164)
    - Testimonies, undated (Box 164)
    - Truck driver's hazards, undated (Box 164)
    - Turkey, undated (Box 184)
    - Unemployment compensation, undated; (2fl) (Box 165)
    - Unemployment compensation, undated (Box 184)
    - Unemployment compensation review board, undated (Box 165)
    - United Auto Workers, undated (Box 165)
    - United Auto workers, undated (Box 184)
    - United Labor Agency, undated; (2 fl) (Box 165)
    - United Agency personnel/grievances, undated (Box 165)
    - United Labor Agency, undated (Box 166)
    - United Labor Agency, undated (Box 176)
    - Video display terminal, undated (Box 166)
    - Wesleyan University, undated (Box 166)
    - Women's Congress, CT, undated (Box 166)
    - Women's Congress, undated (Box 184)
    - Women's employment resources, undated (Box 166)
    - Work and Family Conference, undated (Box 176)
    - Workers compensation, undated (Box 166)
    - Workers' compensation, undated (Box 184)
    - Workers' Institute for Safety and Health, undated (Box 184)
    - Workforce, undated (Box 166)
    - Yale University, undated (Box 166)
  - Subseries H: Government Departments, undated, 1981-1985
    - Administrative Services, Department of, undated; (3 fl) (Box 167)
    - Administrative Services Personnel Division, undated (Box 184)
    - Attorney General, CT, undated; (2 fl) (Box 167)
    - Board of Higher Education, undated (Box 167)
    - Business Regulation, Department of, undated (Box 167)
    - Economic Development, Department of, undated (Box 167)
    - Economic Development Department, undated (Box 184)
    - Education Department, undated (Box 184)
    - Employment and Security Appeals, undated (Box 167)
    - Employment Security Division, undated (Box 184)
    - Energy and Public Utilities, undated (Box 167)
    - Ethics Commission, undated (Box 167)
    - Governor of Connecticut, undated; (2 fl) (Box 167)
    - Governor O'Neill, undated (Box 184)
    - Health Care Cost Containment Task Force, undated (Box 167)
    - Higher Education Department, undated (Box 184)
    - Human Resources, Department of, undated (Box 167)
    - Human Resources Department, undated (Box 184)
    - Joint Commission in Legislative Management, undated (Box 167)
    - Judicial Department, undated (Box 167)
    - Labor, Commission of, undated (Box 167)
    - Labor, U.S. Department of, undated (Box 167)
    - National Labor Relations Act, undated (Box 167)
    - Public Safety Department, undated (Box 184)
    - Revenue, Department of, undated (Box 167)
    - State Board of Education, CT, undated (Box 167)
    - State Secretary, CT, undated (Box 167)
    - Transportation Department, undated (Box 184)
    - U.S. Congress, members of, undated (Box 167)
    - U.S. Senate, members of, undated (Box 167)
    - Women, Permanent Commission on Status, undated (Box 167)
- Series X: Films, undated, 1970-1976
  - Good Work for Democracy, undated (Box 168)
  - Your Next President, 1970 (Box 168)
  - G. Meany, undated (Box 168)
  - The Work Ahead, undated (Box 168)
  - History of American Labor, undated (Box 168)
  - AFL-CIO Centennial Moments, undated (Box 169)
  - Your Next President, 1976 (Box 169)
  - Right Wing Machine, undated (Box 169)
  - Senior Citizens on Medicare, undated (Box 170)
  - A Mighty Fine Union, undated (Box 170)
  - People and Power, undated (Box 170)
  - 60 Minutes Made in Japan, undated (Box 171)
  - J. F. Kennedy's Last Words to Labor, undated (Box 171)
  - People in Politics, undated (Box 171)
- Series XI: Michael Noonan, 1985-1987
  - Governor's Conference on Insurance Availability, 1985 (Box 188)
  - Taskforce to Study Health Care Liability Insurance Cost, 1985 (Box 188)
  - Taskforce on Insurance Availability background, 1985-1986 (Box 188)
  - Small Business and Insurance Reform, 1986 (Box 188)
  - Connecticut Alliance for Insurance Reform (CAIR) I, 1986 (Box 188)
  - Connecticut Alliance for Insurance Reform (CAIR)II, 1987 (Box 189)